<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ctf | Simone Magnani</title><link>https://s41m0n.github.io/category/ctf/</link><atom:link href="https://s41m0n.github.io/category/ctf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>ctf</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Â© Copyright `2022` Simone Magnani</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 11:08:39 +0200</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://s41m0n.github.io/media/me.png</url><title>ctf</title><link>https://s41m0n.github.io/category/ctf/</link></image><item><title>IDCAS</title><link>https://s41m0n.github.io/project/idcas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 11:08:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://s41m0n.github.io/project/idcas/</guid><description>&lt;p>Intrusion Detection and Counter Attack System (IDCAS) is an open source tool developed to be used during CaptureTheFlag (CTF) Attack/Defense cyber security competitions. It provides both full system and single service monitoring, looking for incoming malicious HTTP requests. In fact, during such competitions, while you try to steal other participants secret information to get points, they will try to hack your system stealing yours. IDCAS detects when your system has been compromised and, while it cannot block the attack since it is prohibited in CTF, it will replay the same malicious request to all the other teams.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>IDCAS exploits the use of eBPF and XDP, monitoring the system from the bottom to the top.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more information, please visit the project website (Code tag above ðŸ”).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IPCAS</title><link>https://s41m0n.github.io/project/ipcas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 11:08:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://s41m0n.github.io/project/ipcas/</guid><description>&lt;p>Intrusion Prevention and Counter Attack System (IPCAS) is an open source tool developed to be used during CaptureTheFlag (CTF) Attack/Defense cyber security competitions. It provides full service monitoring, looking for incoming malicious HTTP requests. In fact, during such competitions, while you try to steal other participants secret information to get points, they will try to hack your system stealing yours. IPCAS detects when your system has been compromised and, while it prevents the attack to be successful by providing a fake flag to the attacker, it will replay the same malicious request to all the other teams.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>IPCAS exploits mitmproxy, monitoring and forwarding request to the specified service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more information, please visit the project website (Code tag above ðŸ”).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>